<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://alexpickering.netlify.com//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://alexpickering.netlify.com//" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-02-18T18:40:37-05:00</updated><id>https://alexpickering.netlify.com//feed.xml</id><title type="html">Reasonable Doubts</title><subtitle>An exploration of themes in philosophy, science, language, and life broadly through the lens of a ex-Christian secular humanist and  aspiring rationalist.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Shouting Into the Void</title><link href="https://alexpickering.netlify.com//formalities/2019/12/16/intro.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Shouting Into the Void" /><published>2019-12-16T13:52:41-05:00</published><updated>2019-12-16T13:52:41-05:00</updated><id>https://alexpickering.netlify.com//formalities/2019/12/16/intro</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alexpickering.netlify.com//formalities/2019/12/16/intro.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;or-an-uneasy-foray-into-conversing-alone&quot;&gt;or An Uneasy Foray Into Conversing Alone&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, I was informed by one of my favorite podcasts that blogs are dead.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; As is my nature, I have decided to take this time to announce my journey into the wonderous ruins of the blogdom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://preview.redd.it/uo397ulse8231.jpg?width=883&amp;amp;format=pjpg&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;s=a2d9851d4fbd758ede943480575167c1c9c9cfeb&quot; alt=&quot;Outer Wilds Nomai Writing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;It was such a technologically advanced society. I wonder what happened…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of my life, I have pursued thought provoking conversations, occasionally to the exclusion of more profitable ventures. As a college trained writer (B.A. in English from Ohio State University&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;) with interests in technology, stories and storytelling, and navigating societal turmoil via rational conversation, the next step in my development seemed obvious: go to the digital wishing well, and toss in my two cents (more metal than water in there these days, but I’ll get to that).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the idea of conversing without an interlocutor makes me a bit nervous. To paraphrase Mortimer Adler,&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; we’re playing a game of catch, you and I, and, as such, it’s in my best interest to throw in a way you can’t help but catch. I’ll be doing my damnedest to convey exactly what I mean, but I can’t really know if you’re catching it without feedback. To that end, I welcome responses to the ideas presented here. If I never fail, I never grow, and I’ve already wasted too much time being okay. &lt;strong&gt;I don’t want to be okay.&lt;/strong&gt; I want to be &lt;em&gt;better.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-to-that-nobody-goes-there-anymore-its-too-crowded&quot;&gt;Getting to That: Nobody Goes There Anymore; It’s Too Crowded&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As discussed on the podcast I mentioned earlier&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, the medium is pretty saturated. Everyone has thoughts and opinions, everyone thinks they’re special and worthy of your attention, everyone has a blog, or vlog, or podcast, or YouTube channel they’d love you to read, watch, like, favorite, or subscribe to. I get that, and I have no illusions about being &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; definitive content creator (&lt;em&gt;cringe&lt;/em&gt;) for you. Mostly because I’m new to this. And we can only ever start from the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, I wouldn’t be telling the whole truth if I didn’t say this: I hope you stick around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best,
Alex Pickering&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=L3m-5SmkSYg&amp;amp;t=48m10s&quot;&gt;Hello Internet #131&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Yeah, yeah, “The” Ohio State University. I thought that sounded pretentious since day one, and &lt;em&gt;I’m&lt;/em&gt; usually the one being accused of pretension. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;“The mistake here is to suppose that receiving communication is like receiving a blow or a legacy or a judgment from the court. On the contrary, the reader or listener is much more like the catcher in a game of baseball.” ― Mortimer J. Adler, How to Read a Book &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">or An Uneasy Foray Into Conversing Alone A few weeks ago, I was informed by one of my favorite podcasts that blogs are dead.1 As is my nature, I have decided to take this time to announce my journey into the wonderous ruins of the blogdom. It was such a technologically advanced society. I wonder what happened… Most of my life, I have pursued thought provoking conversations, occasionally to the exclusion of more profitable ventures. As a college trained writer (B.A. in English from Ohio State University2) with interests in technology, stories and storytelling, and navigating societal turmoil via rational conversation, the next step in my development seemed obvious: go to the digital wishing well, and toss in my two cents (more metal than water in there these days, but I’ll get to that). Of course, the idea of conversing without an interlocutor makes me a bit nervous. To paraphrase Mortimer Adler,3 we’re playing a game of catch, you and I, and, as such, it’s in my best interest to throw in a way you can’t help but catch. I’ll be doing my damnedest to convey exactly what I mean, but I can’t really know if you’re catching it without feedback. To that end, I welcome responses to the ideas presented here. If I never fail, I never grow, and I’ve already wasted too much time being okay. I don’t want to be okay. I want to be better. Getting to That: Nobody Goes There Anymore; It’s Too Crowded As discussed on the podcast I mentioned earlier1, the medium is pretty saturated. Everyone has thoughts and opinions, everyone thinks they’re special and worthy of your attention, everyone has a blog, or vlog, or podcast, or YouTube channel they’d love you to read, watch, like, favorite, or subscribe to. I get that, and I have no illusions about being the definitive content creator (cringe) for you. Mostly because I’m new to this. And we can only ever start from the beginning. Still, I wouldn’t be telling the whole truth if I didn’t say this: I hope you stick around. Best, Alex Pickering Hello Internet #131 &amp;#8617; &amp;#8617;2 Yeah, yeah, “The” Ohio State University. I thought that sounded pretentious since day one, and I’m usually the one being accused of pretension. &amp;#8617; “The mistake here is to suppose that receiving communication is like receiving a blow or a legacy or a judgment from the court. On the contrary, the reader or listener is much more like the catcher in a game of baseball.” ― Mortimer J. Adler, How to Read a Book &amp;#8617;</summary></entry></feed>